# Shiva Srinivasan

# Sr QA Engineer

Methodical Senior QA Engineer, mentor and author experienced in software development processes and optimal testing strategies. Helps teams produce exceptional products by offering in-depth quality assurance support. Open and clear communicator with good multitasking skills, organized nature and strong attention to detail. Expert Cypress and Selenium user.

# **Work History**

## 2020-01 -Current

## Senior Quality Assurance Engineer

CrowdStreet, Portland, OR

- Replace existing codeless automation with a new Cypress based CI/CD framework which reduces test execution time from 5hrs to 35 minutes and save over \$2500 annually
- Mentor engineering team on writing scalable and maintainable tests
- Increase technical documentation to improve onboarding efficiency
- Propose development and testing improvements to positively impact usability, function and performance and aid early feedback.
- Assess current process and make propose path for continuous improvement that align with the organization's goals

## 2015-06 -2019-12

## Sr QA Engineer

Navex Global Inc, Portland, OR

- Designed and implemented selenium based automation framework
- Instilled culture of Quality in the organization
- Introduced process improvements that aided early feedback from customers
- Mentored new QA engineers and provide support
- Was the subject matter expert for all identity and access management related queries

## Contact

#### **Address**

Beaverton, OR, 97008

#### Phone

720-233-2416

#### E-mail

sivkumar.s@gmail.com

#### LinkedIn

www.linkedin.com/in/sivkumars

### **Technical Skills**

Jira

**Excellent** 

C#

Very Good

SQL

Very Good

Selenium

Very Good

Cypress

Very Good

Git

Very Good

Team City

0000

# 2009-01 - Application Developer/Conversion Lead

CenturyLink, Vancouver, WA

- Built performance optimization solutions reducing operation costs by over 50% with \$120K annual savings
- Designed real time reporting tools to track conversion timelines and accuracy
- Spearheaded multiple development projects post conversion driving continuous improvement to processes, systems, work flow and customer responsiveness

# 2005-01 - Application Developer

Qwest, Denver, CO

- Recruited to develop and maintain a mission critical application
- Responsible to deliver solutions that meet business objectives ensuring adherence to change management processes Key contributions
- Implemented process improvements and designed automated solutions increasing service levels and stability
- Provided CPU reduction solutions on multiple legacy applications saving over \$500k annually
- Reduced the application downtime by optimizing cycle times on nightly batch activities

# **Education**

2013-01

2009-01

# 2000-01 - Bachelor Degree: Electronics and Communication Engineering

# **Accomplishments**

- Conceptualized and designed Selenium/c# based automation framework
- Performance optimization that resulted in savings of over \$500k annually

Very Good

Jenkins



**AWS** 

Good

Javascript



Node.js



React



## **Expertise**

Domain Knowledge



Strategic planning



CI/CD Implementation



Automation knowledge



Training and mentoring



Team Leadership

